all right what is up guys welcome back
to another video you guys already know
set and forget army appreciate you guys
for you know coming back we've been
uploading youtube videos like crazy
we've been consistent on youtube for
about maybe
three months i've been taking kind of
youtube series you guys already know i'm
doing an educational video every single
tuesday and a podcast every single uh
friday which they have been going and
saying like the feedback i've been
getting is you know ridiculous so shout
out to you guys appreciate all the love
you guys have been giving me so i want
to make this video um not only to help
you guys you guys know i'm posting so
much free in my telegram i have a
free telegram i'm just gonna pop it up
right here where i'm posting a bunch of
educational stuff um you guys can
literally just go here and go check it
out it's just like literally a bunch of
educational stuff i really walk you
through basically free signals um on my
free telegram if you guys want to join
the free telegram just click the link
below um like and i realize what i'm
teaching you guys in the free telegram
is just like a free basic um swing
trading strategy so i'm like you know
what let me do a youtube video on the
best forex swing trading strategy part
one i just want to set the foundation
for you guys for the upcoming videos um
you guys know i don't have a course i
don't have any like nothing all i do is
a boot camp occasionally here and there
with limited seating and i have my
signals but my signal room is closed i'm
coming out with an app in the next 15 to
20 days once the app comes out you guys
come over and then hop on to the signal
switch we are in a nine week winning
streak let me see if i can actually pop
that up right now actually so this is
the actual spreadsheet of my my
journaling of my signals for the past i
think seven weeks as you guys can tell
this is the percentage that i'm making
per week every single week only risking
one percent i need you guys to
understand that this is only one percent
if i were to risk two percent this total
number would double to uh basically like
164 because that's double so let's say
this week we made nine percent if you
risk two percent you would have made 18
14 here you would have made 30. you
would have made 50
so currently right now we are on a nice
nice winning streak so um let's i'm
gonna open up the signal room and then
let's let's keep this uh ball rolling so
the best forex swing trading strategy
part one right so before anything i want
you guys to understand my time frame do
you guys need to understand if we're
gonna be swing trading or trading on the
higher time frames you got to have these
time frames up here when i realized on
the boot camp with some of the students
is they didn't even have them favored it
they just had them like this without
there so subconsciously like you you're
not reminding yourself all you're
basically focused on is the four hour
two hour one hour no you need to pop up
the higher time frames you need to have
them there because you just
subconsciously will always see it when
you're flickering up and down the time
frames and you just click on it you need
to see it the most important thing about
this business is you need to see what is
happening if you are only seeing these
time frames right here you simply don't
know what's happening under the time
frames if you're only focusing on price
right here you're like you're too like
into the charger to like like a horse or
just focus on like what's in front of
you you're not even realizing that
you're actually selling or buying at a
level that is used as support and
resistance in the past right these are
all crucial things and it comes down to
a very simple foundation that is you
need to see what you're looking at right
so this is why i like you know just
sitting back pushing my chair back just
a little bit enough to be able to
analyze what is going on
so the foundation of a swing trader i
think any trader in general it should be
start off on the higher time frame go
out to the weekly go out to the monthly
and what are we doing just get the
overall flow just zoom out obviously
this is too far but you want to zoom in
on what's going on i would want to say
max
um so we're in 2018 here so let's just
call it four or five years so you just
want to focus on four or five years of
price which would be basically this
right here so you just zoom in and then
you only focus on what's relevant right
as you can tell we had price go bearish
then we kind of went bullish and we're
basically right now at a zone where if
you notice if you just zoom out you get
the bigger picture
where the support level just overall
doesn't matter like if you don't see
what's going on you know that when price
comes into this level and we are above
it we're simply buying if we are under
we're obviously selling and in this case
we're above it so this is a good sign so
you want to be buying right so this is
where after you've identified that we're
one out of support and two we're
basically bullish now you understand all
right the higher timeframes are bullish
let's see what i can find on the daily
time frame all right so now the daily
time frame people make the same mistake
they'll look at the chart too far like
this trying to focus on the same four
years or whatever the cases or try to
have the same chart um open and it's
crucial because you can't even see the
wigs or candlesticks you gotta focus on
what matters so i always say on the
weekly focus on four years and when it
comes to the daily focus on two years
max like just focus on what's going on
right here so when you zoom in to actual
price you can see what is going on like
you can actually see all of the
candlesticks you could properly identify
a level of let's just say here it's
resistance use a support you can check
you're dragging it down support
resistance resistant support resistance
so on and so forth right you can't
identify these levels if you're way too
well right
so two very important things make sure
you identify where we are on the weekly
timeframe are we bullish are we bearish
are we at a support level resistance and
when you're on the daily zoom in zoom in
enough that you can properly identify
these levels of resistance that are used
as support and you can properly see the
candlesticks right after doing so you
need to identify obviously where are we
on the daily are we at a resistance are
we out of support you need to understand
that if whatever you're doing on the
weekly you want it to roll over on the
daily on the four hour two hour one hour
you need all of these
confluences to come together you need to
understand that if you're bullish on the
weekly bearish on the daily bullish in
the four hour
just consolidating on the one hour
you're just like nothing is looking good
you're literally just chopping you want
everything to be bullish so then you're
just going with the wave you're like in
this game we're not gonna create our own
wave it's i know it sucks it's crazy
like it is what it is like it's just not
gonna happen here you gotta go with
whatever the market gives you and if the
market is giving you nothing you do
nothing if the market is giving you
down you go down if the market is giving
you up you go up and that's all we do as
traders is find an opportunity to get in
on one of those moves so in this example
right here obviously we're identified
we're at the weekly level of support
you go down to the daily we are now
above
a daily level of resistance as you get
you guys can go to the free telegram or
you guys want to join the free telegram
the link is in the description below so
in the free title game i updated this
trade exactly when we were doing this so
the moment we broke above it i was like
all right cool bet i can't do nothing
now i can't buy right now simply because
i'm just buying in la la land i'm
literally buying in the middle of
nowhere i need price to come back use
the same level that it used as
resistance as resistance resistance
resistance resistance resistance to use
it as support to then go long what a
coincidence that this same exact
thing that i'm waiting for here happened
right here look at the same break above
the same reaches and in the push right
so this is where i have waited for the
price to come back and one thing is this
is very easy to explain and you know
just be like oh yeah cool i'm gonna go
now to the charts and do it but no like
this doesn't happen always perfectly all
the time
this is what i teach in the boot camp
and the signal room like i can go and
show you perfect examples all the time
but perfect examples don't come all the
time you guys need to understand that
that's what a lot of gurus do they just
show you like the cleanest trade and
then that's what they just base off the
whole entire course or whatever no i
base it off of reality and what's
happening right now is reality
we had the pool back just because you
had the pullback doesn't mean that you
can buy that's basically what i just
told you you could do here you could
just wait for the pullback and then you
buy it no notice how this pullback has
now closed under the resistance notice
how here how this has pulled back but it
closed above
this has pulled back and it has closed
under meaning you can't buy because
you're going to simply just hit your
head at this resistance level right here
which is not ideal you would need for
price to get above that resistance again
come back and retest and then go so if
you notice here we just all of this time
i'm updating in the signal i'm like guys
we're not doing nothing we're trading a
bunch of other players that look a lot
cleaner versus what's going on here so
we would go down to the four hour
and after we finally get the break out
of the four hour notice this is just a
consolidation zone notice what i had
said at the beginning you identify where
we are in the weekly daily four hour and
as you can notice four hours bullish
daily was under resistance four hour was
consolidating at this point so what do
you do simply nothing you just sit back
and wait for the trade to give you the
right move so at this point right here
we've identified that now we've got in
the push up
now we're waiting for the retest of the
area of interest right here along with
the ema
this is where you get your entry signal
and this is basically where we are right
now just continuing the trade to the
upside i personally did not take this
trade simply because i was trading other
pairs right now which i think i'm
floating in profit yeah so i'm actually
floating very nicely in profit on
gj let me actually just show you guys
the trade so show you guys that this is
a
no cap zone
i'm not going to show you guys the
actual account size but you guys could
see
right there
floating currently right now about like
5k
in profit we're just doing good um sent
this trade out earlier in the signal
group um
but it goes with the same foundation
what are we doing on the weekly what are
we doing
up what are we doing on the daily up
what are we doing on the four hour up
what are we doing at two hour up
everything is up so i'm looking to go up
with the signal is that simple you get
me obviously there's a lot more that
goes like so much more that goes into it
stop loss placement entry signal ema
structure lower time frame like there's
just a lot more that goes into it but i
just obviously this is only part one i'm
going to create a series of this video
and if you guys basically want to see
more of it uh make sure to join the free
telegram make sure to turn on your
notifications make sure to stay tuned to
my instagram and my um
uh updates when it comes out to the app
because the app i'm gonna be dropping
some gems in there i'm just gonna like
create my own instagram within the app i
don't wanna keep mixing my instagram
with like my regular life and then
trading it's just like a big mix so
anything trading related i'm gonna post
in the app so um yeah appreciate you
guys watching the video to the end i
hope this sets a very nice and simple
gem foundation to what is to come in the
next series of the you know forex
trading strategy simplified for
beginners so um yeah please give me some
feedback you guys feedback means
everything i hope this is very simple
might have been a little bit fast but i
just wanted to get the message across of
what is to come but i have to create the
foundation first so you guys can be able
to understand everything that is to come
in the future so appreciate you guys for
watching the video and i'll see you guys
in friday's podcast take it easy guys